Mikael Jönsson

ENGINEERING MANAGER

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikjonsson/ Gothenburg, Sweden

experience summary

Management ~3 years

As an Engineering Manager at Unifaun, Implementation Manager at Jeppesen and Quality Engineering Team Lead at Atlassian.

Leadership ~10 years

Test/QA Lead and management roles including my previous role as Quality Assistance Engineer. Note that some leadership experience overlaps with management experience as the roles mean both, including my current role as an Engineering Manager.

SW Industry ~14 years

education

Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering, LTH, Lund, Sweden

technical summary

Note: This is just a selection, not a full listing, and skill levels vary.

Programming & Scripting languages

Scala, Java, NodeJS, TypeScript, Python, C# and HTML.

Databases

DynamoDB, Oracle, MS SQL Server and PostgreSQL.

Operating systems

Windows, Mac, Windows Server and Linux.

Software applications & tools

JIRA, Confluence, Bitbucket (and many other Atlassian products), FogBugz,
Sharepoint, Git, GitHub, Subversion, Jenkins, Fiddler, Wireshark, Microsoft Office, MS Visual Studio,
IntelliJ IDEA and Eclipse.

Other

Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microservices and Docker.

experience

Unifaun | Engineering Manager | Feb 2020 - Present

Wide range of duties including managing two of our engineering teams at our Gothenburg office;

One team is a traditional feature development and Scrum team.

The other is a mix of infrastructure, operations, architecture and QA. Heading up this team also means I'm accountable for our platform availability and uptime.

Technologies include: Java, Typescript, Linux, LXD & Docker.

Social & people skills include: Hiring, Growing, Mentoring, Coaching & Leading engineers.

Tools include: Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket, SonarQube & Jenkins.

Unifaun | QA | Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

Introducing, improving and implementing processes, tools and systems, as well as development practices, to increase quality & developer experience.

Technologies include: Java, Typescript, Linux, LXD & Docker.

Tools include: Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket, SonarQube & Jenkins.

Good Solutions AB | QA Manager | Jun 2018 — Aug 2019

Introducing, improving and implementing processes, tools and systems, as well as coaching development practices, to reach shippable quality faster and enable scaling (of customer base and number of employees).

I also do hands-on system development, test automation, testing, project management and product management.

Technologies include: C#, JavaScript, Java, Python, Windows, Linux & Docker.

Tools include: Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket & Bamboo.

MediCase | Quality Assurance & Software Testing | Sep 2017 — May 2018

Defining and implementing good software QA and development processes & practices, including tool support, for a product used in a clinical research domain.

Introducing and implementing test automation. I also do hands on manual testing and minor system development.

Technologies include: C#, JavaScript, TypeScript & Azure.

Jeppesen, a Boeing Company | Implementation Manager | Jan 2017 — Jul 2017

Line management for \sim 15 individuals and 3 teams that are working in customer facing projects.

experience

Atlassian | Quality Engineering Team Lead | Jul 2015 — Dec 2016

Building and managing a team of Quality Engineers working with development teams that maintain and develop a mix of front- and backend products and services for Atlassian's Cloud offerings.

Working together with engineers, teams and stakeholders to enable fast and safe continuous deployment of our microservices, by using and defining/evolving CI/CD, DevOps, development and engineering good practices.

Techniques & technologies include: CQRS, EventSourcing, Feature Flagging, AWS, Scala, Java, NodeJS and more.

Social & people skills include: Hiring, Growing, Mentoring, Coaching & Leading top talents with high diversity.

Tools include: Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket, Fisheye, Crucible & Bamboo.

Atlassian | QA (Quality Assistance) Engineer | Mar 2014 — Jun 2015

Focusing on the backend of Atlassian's cloud products and microservices, using many of our tools on a daily basis in a Java, Scala and Python heavy environment.

Being a Quality Engineer (formerly Quality Assistance Engineer) at Atlassian is not the same as being a tester, as we favor preventing and mitigating issues before and during development by coaching developers and improving the development processes, as opposed to traditional late stage testing.

Vehco (AddSecure) | Tester and Test Lead | Apr 2013 — Mar 2014

Working with many of Vehco's products for Fleet Management including PDAs, vehicle mounted devices, desktop, web, cloud and server solutions, as well as integrations with customer systems.

Autodesk | Sr. SQA Engineer, QA Lead | Feb 2012 - Mar 2013

Mostly working with the Autodesk Showcase Professional and Opticore Studio teams and products, as well as test automation frameworks for rendering and saving images from Autodesk Invetor and Revit in the advanced rendering team.

Spotfire, TIBCO | Sr. Member Technical Staff, QA | Jan 2008 - Jan 2012

Project Lead Coordinating the consolidation and migration of two bug management systems to one new system.

Test Lead including two of Spotfire's larger projects and a few minor projects.

Tester Main area of experience is manual scripted and exploratory testing of the entire Spotfire product stack, with some experience in automated testing

UIQ Technology | Test Engineer | May 2007 - Dec 2007

Built up and drove unit- and functional testing for the UIQ Kits team and its components.